Snodgrass, W.D. mss., 1984-2013 LMC 2823
Lilly Library
Snodgrass, W.D. mss.
1984-2013
Lilly Library
Snodgdrass, W.D. (William De Witt), 1926-2009
LMC 2823
2 Linear Feet 2 boxes
The Snodgrass, W. D. mss., 1984-2013, consists of the original and photocopied correspondence, emails, obituaries, and tributes concerning the illness and death of W. D. Snodgrass, 1926-2009. Most correspondence and emails are between Snodgrass's friends and colleagues and his fourth wife, writer Kathleen Snodgrass.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift: 2014
Biographical Note
W. D. Snodgrass was born in Wilkinsburg, Pennsylvania, on January 5, 1926. He studied at Geneva College before serving in the United States Navy during World War II. After leaving the Navy, Snodgrass finished his BA (1949) at the University of Iowa, where he also completed an MA in English (1951) and an MFA in Creative Writing (1953). Snodgrass won the Pulitzer Prize for his debut poetry collection, Heart's Needle, in 1960. He published a total of nineteen poetry collections as well as several anthologies and works of literary criticism. Snodgrass married his fourth wife, translator Kathleen Brown, 1950-, in 1985. He died in Erieville, New York, on January 13, 2009.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains original and photocopied correspondence, emails, obituaries, and tributes concerning William De Witt Snodgrass's (1926-2009) illness and death. Most correspondence and emails are between Snodgrass's friends and colleagues and his fourth wife, writer Kathleen Snodgrass.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged at the file level.
Related Materials
See Snodgrass/Segal mss., and Sillitoe mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Poets, American--20th century; Snodgrass, W.D. (William De Witt), 1926-2009; Aleya, Dorothy C. (Dorothy Collins), 1898-1974
- Corr.: Kathy Snodgrass & Don Hall, 2014 (Box 1)
- The Collected Stories of Hortense Calisher (with inscription), 1984 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 2013-2014 (Box 1)
- Kathy (Brown) Snodgrass corresp. with Hortense Calisher, 1984-1998 (Box 1)
- Kathy Snodgrass corresp. with Donald Hall, 2008-2013 (Box 1)
- Copy of More Daring Escapes: Poems Steven Huff (Box 2)
- Goyen (Box 2)
- DeLoss McGraw Mickey Mouse (Box 2)
- Handwritten Diary kept by Kathy Snodgrass recording treatment and progression of W.D. Snodgrass' final illness (Box 2)
- Emails & Letters, Oct.-Dec. 2008 (Box 2)
- Condolences, (3 folders) (Box 2)
- Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 2)
- Obituaries & Tributes (Box 2)
- Items from the library of W.D. Snodgrass (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Folder contains originals of poems, various poets and dates.